Guide to the Social Ethics Pamphlet Collection
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Student Papers, Series III
  - A
    - A world civilization in retrospect, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Facilities for social studies in American theological seminaries, n.d. (Box 95, Folder 15)
    - Local church programs for social action, 1948 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Annotated bibliography and project outline on the topic of Southern clergymen and slavery (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Reflections resulting from participation in Freedom Vote Campaign, Mississippi, October - November, 1963 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - In the garden of tomorrow: the relevance of eugenics to social ethics, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Eugenics; Medical ethics
    - Trends in contemporary anti-semitism in the United States, 1943 (Box 96, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Antisemitism
    - Mexican migrant workers and the Farm Labor Program (Box 96, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Labor movement; Migrant labor
    - The nature of religious diversity on campus, n.d. (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Mrs. Elizabeth Eloise Dilling, 1944 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - The Southern Regional Council, 1951 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Community organization; Race relations; Southern States
    - A platform for democracy in America, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - A platform for democracy in America, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Agriculture; Economic policy; Labor movement; Rural conditions
    - A study of the recent influx of southern Negroes into the Dixwell area, 1958 (Box 64, Folder 8)
      Subjects: African Americans; New Haven; Race relations
    - A proposal for a missionary parish for New Haven, 1950 (Box 64, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Christian communities; New Haven; Religion and culture
    - Christianity and Communism: the historical background and analysis of the Church today in Soviet Russia, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Communism; Religion and culture
    - The problem of the segregated Negro synods in the Presbyterian Church, U.S.A., 1955 (Box 64, Folder 11)
      Subjects: African Americans; Presbyterians; Race relations; Religion and culture
    - Lenin, 1948 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Freedom? Maybe, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Labor movements
  - B
    - Social ills and social change as revealed and fostered by current comics (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - The Church and Race, 1947 (Box 64, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Civil rights; Religion and culture; World War, 1939-1945
    - The melting pot, twenty years of melting, the catalyst, 1945 (Box 65, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Immigrants; Religion and culture
    - Postwar planning in New Haven, 1944 (Box 64, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Community organization; New Haven
    - A study of three urban churches particularly in regard to the problem of communication, 1964 (Box 64, Folder 17)
      Subjects: African Americans; Religion and culture
    - Untitled, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 18)
      Subject: Labor movements
    - What is democracy?, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Untitled, 1947 (Box 65, Folder 2)
      Comment: includes a pamphlet from The Children's Center orphanage (Hamden)
    - Ladies, Elephants and Donkeys or Women's Political Role, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      Subjects: United States--politics and government; Women
      Comments: includes clippings from women's magazines about 1952 presidential elections
    - A year of Life being an experiment in content analysis: an application of content analysis techniques to the editorials of Life magazine, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 4)
      Subjects: American periodicals
    - Communism and academic freedom, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Academic freedom; Communism
    - The Chinese race problem - a brief study of race prejudice in its Philippine setting, n.d. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - The churches and the Japanese-Americans, 1945 (Box 65, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Race relations; Religion and culture; World War, 1939-1945; Japanese-Americans
    - Interracial marriage, 1947 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - The possibility of Christian burial in Connecticut, 1951 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Critical studies of a boy in a foster home and some of the agencies dealing with him (Box 65, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Child care; New Haven
    - The southern Tenant Farmer's Union, 1942 (Box 65, Folder 9a)
    - More than a minister: a study in rural life, 1941 (Box 65, Folder 12)
    - A Critique of the social gospel, 1945 (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Denominational out-marriage: a measure of religious loyalty, 1962 (Box 65, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Marriage; Religion and culture
    - The Negro problem in America and its relation to the race problem in world politics, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 15)
      Subjects: African Americans; International relations; Race relations
    - Juvenile delinquency in New Philadelphia, Ohio, 1950 (Box 65, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Juvenile delinquency
    - The lost and the found: a study of emotionally disturbed children and the society from which they come, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Problems of unionization of the Nashville branch of the Methodist Publishing House, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Labor movement; Methodists
    - Carmen Jones: how may such a musical production influence racial thinking, feeling and acting?, 1944
      Subjects: Box 66 Folder 3
    - The West Hills housing project: a wartime community, 1944 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      Subjects: New Haven; Public housing
    - Poor man's justice, 1940 (Box 66, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Civil rights; Labor movement
    - A report on migrant work in Berrien County, Michigan, n.d. (Box 66, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Agriculture; Labor movement; Migrant labor
    - Some aspects of New Haven labor unions in the past few years, 1940 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Labor movement; New Haven
    - Negro sects, 1945 (Box 66, Folder 8)
      Subjects: African Americans; Race relations; Religion and culture; Sects
    - Race relations and New Haven church youth, 1943 (Box 66, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Church work and students; New Haven; Race relations
    - Student political action movements in America, 1946 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Some remarks on Christian family ethics, 1943 (Box 66, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Family; Religion and culture
    - The central city parish of the protestant church, 1953 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Social action in the Virginia annual conference 1935-1955 (Box 66, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Methodist; Race relations; Religion and culture
    - A study of stratification within Guilford Congregational Church, Guilford, Connecticut, 1955 (Box 66, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Guilford, Connecticut; Religion and culture
    - An analysis of the labor-mamnagement pronouncements of the Presbyterian Church, U.S.A., 1951 (Box 66, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Labor movement; Presbyterians; Religion and culture
    - Farm hands and preachers: a preliminary report on a statistical study of the church participation patterns in a rural community in central New York state, 1952 (Box 66, Folder 16)
    - A cost of living study of married students enrolled at the Yale Divinity School, 1948 (Box 66, Folder 17)
      Subjects: Education; New Haven; Yale University
    - The Pros and Cons of a Compulsory National Health Program, 1949 (Box 96, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Medical Care; Social Legislation; United States-politics and government
    - Swampland, 1950 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Comment: includes census and other demographic data for New Haven.
    - The Protestant strategy used in an attempt to defeat the school bus bill, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - A church and community survey of Glasgow, Kentucky: a study and analysis of a community emphasis program in the development of moral and spiritual values in a farm-factory town, 1953 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Agriculture; Church work with students; Community organization; Education; Race relations; Religion and culture
    - Whittle while you work: an analysis of the problem of race relations from personal observation, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      Subjects: African Americans; Race relations
    - Negro-White Intermarriage in New Haven, 1945 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - The History, program and evaluation of the Dixwell Group, 1944 (Box 67, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Community organization; New Haven; Race relations; Religion and culture
    - The American church and the world population problem, 1958 (Box 67, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Church and world
    - Current relations between Christians and Communists on the mission field, 1948 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Church and the world
    - A Study of the Wagner-Murray-Dingell Bill: Why, What, and Where to From Where?, 1945 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Medical care; Social legislation; United States-politics and government
      Comment: about the debate on a national health care program between 1942 and 1953
    - A study of the response of Akron churches to the social needs of the community, 1953 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - A study of the relationship between the New Haven Y.M.C.A. and the churches of the city, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - A study of the Alcoholics Anonymous groups of New Haven, 1952 (Box 67, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Alcoholism; New Haven
    - Migrants arise!, n.d. (Box 67, Folder 11)
      Subjects: Agriculture; Labor Movement; Migrant labor; Race relations; Religion and culture
    - Occupational opportunities for Negroes in New Haven above the wage earner level, 1955 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - The church and juvenile delinquency, 1946 (Box 67, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Juvenile delinquency; New Haven; Religion and culture
    - The Lincoln Electric Company incentive system, 1949 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Interviews with ministers and labor leaders on the relation of church and labor in Bridgeport, 1954 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - C
    - Religion in support of segregation in the south, 1956 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - A study of St. Paul's Church, New Haven, 1958 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Episcopal Church; New Haven; Religion and culture
    - An empirical study concerning the role of religion in Negro society as interpreted by contemporary, popular Negro magazines, 1955 (Box 68, Folder 1)
      Subjects: African Americans; American periodicals; Religion and culture
    - A descriptive and critical study of sociological functional analysis, with particular reference to its interpretation of religion, 1955 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - American Japanese and the war, 1942 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Civil rights; United States--politics and government; World War, 1939-1945
    - Use of religious motion pictures in 75 protestant churches in greater New Haven, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - The hospital chaplaincy in relation to the medical profession, 1954 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - The church and the funeral industry: conflict or cooperation?, 1964 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Regional planning as a proposed answer to the South's problems, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Community organization; Religion and culture; Southern States
    - Teenage leisure and the community of Milford, Connecticut, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Saved, sanctified and baptized by the Holy Spirit: a study of the Mount Hope Temple United Holy Church of America, Inc., 1957 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      Subjects: African Americans; Religion and culture; Sects
    - The E. Ingraham Company and the tariff, 1958 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - R.G. Le Tourneau- The man and his work, 1946 (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - A platform for American democracy (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Cooperation as a means of social change, 1952 (Box 68, Folder 12)
      Comment: includes by-laws and other materials from the New Haven co-op
    - Recreational facilities in the Catholic churches of New Haven, 1944 (Box 68, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Catholic church; Church work with students; New Haven
    - Recent American policy toward China, 1947 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Trial and error: a study of political apathy in New Haven, 1952 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - The radical Negro protest against the public school system in Virginia, 1951 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - A study of the historical background of the rise of Formosan nationalism and independence movement, 1967 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Subjects: World politics
    - Junior Work Camps, 1944 (Box 69, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Children; Labor movement
    - Juvenile delinquency among Negroes, 1945 (Box 69, Folder 5)
      Subjects: African Americans; Juvenile delinquency
    - Hamden high school boys and how they use their leisure time., 1951 (Box 69, Folder 6)
      Subjects: Children; Church work and students; Youth
    - The problem of armament, 1942 (Box 69, Folder 7)
      Subjects: International relations; World War, 1939-1945
    - Inasmuch as you have done it unto the least of these my brethren, 1944 (Box 69, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Children; Juvenile delinquency; New Haven
      Comment: includes charts outlining the economic and housing demographics of New Haven
    - The Negro in the United States, 1947 (Box 69, Folder 9)
      Comment: contains African American population statistics for all the states from the 1940 census
    - A survey of the recreational facilities for young people in the city of Meriden, Connecticut, 1943 (Box 69, Folder 9a)
      Subjects: Children; Church work with students
    - Community resources and the problems of aging in the city of New Haven, 1955 (Box 69, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Medical care; New Haven
    - A study of the community development plans of two Connecticut towns: Naugatuck and Seymour, 1958 (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Defense Industry and effects on a community (Box 69, Folder 12)
      Subjects: Labor movement; Public housing
    - A study of denominational service committees, with special reference to their history and projects undertaken, their relation to other denominational agencies, and their administration, concluding with some recommendations to Northern Baptists in the light of their present work, 1948 (Box 69, Folder 13)
      Subjects: American Friends; Brethren; Congregational Christian; Northern Baptist; Unitarian; Universalist; Congregational Christian
    - Zionism in America, 1952 (Box 69, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Jews; Zionism
    - An evaluation of the effect of the student Christian movement upon social, political, economic, and religious attitudes and actions of college students, 1943 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Social legislation pending in the Seventy-sixth Congress, third session (Box 70, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Labor movement; Social legislation
    - The appeal of Communism to the American Negro, 1952 (Box 70, Folder 3)
      Subjects: African Americans; Communism; Race relations
    - A critical evaluation of Yale Hope Mission, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 5)
      Subjects: New Haven; Religion and culture; Yale University
      Comment: includes pamphlets and reports from social service agencies in New Haven
    - Christian ethics and policy making in the administration of higher education (Box 70, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Academic freedom; Education; Religion and culture
    - A case study in New Haven city politics: the League of Women Voters and the city charter issue, 1952 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      Subjects: New Haven; United States--politics and government
    - The mad hatters of Norwalk, 1955 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Delinquent girls from broken homes, 1941 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - What is the future of our international exchangees?, 1954 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - The role of religious workers in reformatories for women, 1946 (Box 70, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Correctional institutions; Religion and culture
    - A study of Catholic, Protestant relations and tensions in West Haven, Connecticut, 1948 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Planning commission issue, 1953 (Box 70, Folder 11)
      Comment: this study is specifically about the town of Southington, Connecticut
  - D-F
    - Why are there two separate Negro churches in Danbury, or Danbury clergy attitudes on racial integration in Danbury churches, 1950 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - A study of the role of the church in relation to automation, 1966 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - The Chinese in New Haven: a survey of their situation and needs, 1952 (Box 71, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Immigrants; New Haven; United States--politics and government
    - The Mexican in the United States, n.d. (Box 71, Folder 4)
      Subjects: Immigrants; United States--politics and government
    - Attitudes of New Haven ministers toward the pronouncements of the Federal Council of Churches in the field of industrial relations, 1950 (Box 71, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; Labor movement
    - Religious programs for social action: the NAACP, 1943 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - The control of social diseases in the United States of America, 1943 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - A 71, 1948 (Box 8)
    - Church endowments, 1942 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Fair Haven: The church and the family, 1950 (Box 71, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Family; New Haven; Religion and culture
    - The social significance of the Inter-Varsity Christian Fellowship, 1945 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - The influence of the synagogue on the Jewish community, 1947 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - A liturgy for the social gospel, 1946 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Developing a church program for a residential suburban community, 1951 (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - a study of the New Haven County Temporary Home, 1944 (Box 72, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Children; Juvenile delinquency
    - A casket or a cross: a study of the relationship of the clergy to the funeral director, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 2)
      Comment: includes pamphlets and advertisements for funeral homes and funeral supplies
    - The ethics of economic competition, 1942 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - The Negro's struggle for equality of opportunity and treatment in the United States Army, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 4)
      Subjects: African Americans; Armed forces; Race Relations
    - The proposed union between the Protestant Episcopal Church and the Presbyterian Church, U.S.A., 1943 (Box 72, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Ecumenical movement; Presbyterians; Protestant Episcopal Church
    - Untitled, n.d. (Box 72, Folder 6)
      Comment: the paper is concerned with the zoning battle between a Catholic retreat center and a real estate developer in Middletown, Connecticut.
    - The United Nations and the Palestine Settlement, 1951 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Some proposals for solving the salary problem among Methodist ministers, 1943 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      Subjects: Methodists
    - Freedom of the press, 1941 (Box 72, Folder 9)
      Subjects: American periodicals; Civil rights
    - Report on workshop in intercultural education, 1941 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Religion and the church in the thinking of thirty Methodist preference students at Yale college, 1951 (Box 72, Folder 11)
      Subjects: College students; Methodists; Yale University
    - The church and housing discrimination, 1962 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - The Church of God in the world of men: a study in the social attitudes of ministers and ministerial students in the Church of God, 1947 (Box 72, Folder 13)
      Subjects: Church of God; Religion and culture
    - A paper on birth control: with special reference to action on Bill #317 at the State Legislature, May 1945 Hartford, Connecticut (Box 72, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Birth control; United States--politics and government
    - Southern Baptist thought and sociological data concerning marriage and family life contrasted, 1953 (Box 72, Folder 15)
      Subjects: Religion and culture; Southern Baptists
    - Roman Catholic influence on the New Haven school system: as seen especially in Hamilton and Highland Heights schools, 1950 (Box 72, Folder 16)
      Subjects: Education; New Haven; Roman Catholics
    - Religion, the church and the man in the service, 1943 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Armed forces; Religion and culture
    - Huey P. Long, Dictator of Louisiana, 1944 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - The church and point four, 1951 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Subjects: Church and world; Community organization; International organization
    - Beat Taft! CIO campaign in Dayton, Ohio (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Comment: includes clippings from local and CIO newspapers
    - Zionism on trial, 1950 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Subjects: Israel-Arab conflicts; Judaism-relations-Christianity; Zionism
    - Puerto Ricans in New Haven, 1957 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Christian Missions and UNESCO, 1953 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Religion in Russia before and during the revolution, 1948 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Probation in New Haven, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Subjects: Correctional institutions; New Haven
    - The theology of race, n.d. (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - A strategy toward disaffected groups on the issue of race in local Protestant congregations, 1952 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Elm Haven: A government housing project in New Haven, 1941 (Box 73, Folder 9)
      Subjects: Community organization; New Haven; Public housing
    - Some factors in the religious attitudes of a selected group of Yale undergraduates, 1961 (Box 73, Folder 10)
      Subjects: Church work with students; College students; Religion and culture; Yale University
    - Group study and discussion in the Christian Association, 1954 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - Treatment of juvenile delinquency, 1941 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - Advancement practices among management level personnel: Westinghouse Electric corporation, 1951 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Current anti-Japanese agitation in California, 1945 (Box 73, Folder 14)
      Subjects: Race relations; Japanese Americans
    - The doctor: his relation to the community, 1953 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Program for American democracy (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - A study of juvenile delinquency, 1941 (Box 73, Folder 17)
      Comment: includes map of the towns of Naugatuck, Waterbury and Watertown, Connecticut
    - The adjustment of European exchange students in the United States, 1952 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - An evaluation of the denominational race relations program of the Congregational Christian Churches, 1952 (Box 73, Folder 19)
      Subjects: Congregational Christian Churches; Race relations
    - Radio News, 1947 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - Labor-management-citizens committee of Stamford and Greenwich, 1951 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - Migratory problems in Windsor, Connecticut, 1955 (Box 73, Folder 22)
      Subjects: Migrant labor
    - A study and commentary on co-operative milk distribution, 1951 (Box 73, Folder 23)
  - G-H
    - Race relations in the armed services, 1947 (Box 74, Folder 1)
      Subjects: Armed forces; Race relations
    - A survey of the First Christian Church of Springfield, Massachusetts, 1948 (Box 74, Folder 2)
      Subjects: Disciples of Christ
    - Protestantism in Derby, 1946 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - The U.S. and China: a study of Life magazines editorial policy, 1951 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      Subjects: American periodicals; International relations; China
    - A study of the policy making function of the general board of the National Council of Churches of Christ in America, 1952 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Inclusiveness in the northern urban church, 1960 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - The end of oblivion: a report on the financial structure and support of the Negro and white schools of Muskogee, Oklahoma, 1955 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Pacifist proposals for meeting the problem of international disorder, 1949 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Religion in mass culture and its impact on church members, 1955 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Theological and ethical presuppositions in the Saturday Evening Post, 1955 (Box 74, Folder 9)
      Subjects: American periodicals; Religion and culture